PROFESSOR: So what's the
story about optimality?
There was tree search, there was graph
search, there was admissibility, there
was consistency.
Here's the story.
A star is optimal in tree search if
you have an admissible heuristic.
That's the easy one to think about.
Such tree search is optimal when
the heuristic is admissible.
Uniform cost search is a special case.
Whenever h equals zero, and clearly
h equals zero is admissible.
For graph search, a star is still
optimal, but only if the heuristic
obeys the stronger condition
of consistency.
Uniform cost search is then still
optimal for graph search, because h
equals zero, in addition to being
obviously admissible, is easy to show
that it's also consistent.
So in both cases, uniform cost
search is a special case.
In both cases, a star is optimal.
Tree search requires
only admissibility.
Graph search also requires
consistency.
In general, most natural admissible
heuristics that you'll come up with,
say in the course of doing your project
one, will be consistent if
they're admissible.
That's not always true.
You'll have to be careful.
But in general, things you come up with
especially through relaxations,
if they're admissible, they're
also consistent.